Finding Aid to the Gloria Steinem papers SSC.MS.00237
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS, 1970-96
  - National Women's Political Caucus
    - Correspondence, 1970-71; 1985 (Box 168, Folder 23)
    - Democratic National Conventions: correspondence, clippings, memoranda, printed material, 1972-84 (Box 168, Folder 24)
    - Democratic National Conventions: correspondence, clippings, memoranda, printed material, 1972-84 (Box 169, Folder 1-7)
    - Election of caucus chair, 1989 (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - Financial material, 1972-76 (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - Fundraising: correspondence and memoranda, 1971-72; 1980 (Box 169, Folder 10)
    - General, 1971; undated (Box 169, Folder 11)
    - Legislation: bills, correspondence and memoranda, 1971-77; undated (Box 169, Folder 12)
    - Membership list, 1971 (Box 169, Folder 13)
    - Membership mailings, 1971-74 (Box 169, Folder 14)
    - "Names" file (contacts): correspondence, lists, 1971-73 (Box 169, Folder 15)
    - National Women's Caucus for Art: program, 1980 (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Public Outreach: newsletters, position papers, 1971-73; undated (Box 170, Folder 2-3)
    - Press releases, 1971-76; 1985; undated (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Sample Questions and Answers for Candidates, undated (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - State and city caucuses: correspondence, press releases, newsletters, 1971-74; undated (Box 170, Folder 6-11)
    - Twentieth Anniversary Convention Packet, Washington D.C. 1991 (includes information on depositing of NWPC papers to Schlesinger Library) (Box 170, Folder 12)
  - Voters for Choice
    - Board of Directors
      - Lists, 1981; 1984; undated (Box 170, Folder 13)
      - Memoranda, minutes, and agendas, 1979-86; undated (Box 170, Folder 14-16)
      - By-laws, 1980 (Box 170, Folder 17)
      - Campaigns
        - Candidate lists and contribution guidelines, 1980; 1984; undated (Box 170, Folder 18-20)
        - Handbooks
          - "Campaign Strategy Handbook,", 1982 (Box 170, Folder 20)
          - Winning with Choice, 1986 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1979-84; 1989; undated (Box 171, Folder 2)
    - Financial records, 1980-81; 1984 (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - Fundraising: donor lists, events, and general, 1979-81; 1986; undated (Box 171, Folder 4-6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - Outreach: mailings, newsletters, fact sheets, 1980; 1983; undated (Box 171, Folder 8-9)
    - Press releases, 1980; 1984; 1994 (Box 171, Folder 10)
    - Research materials
      - Clippings, articles, and printed material, 1970-86 (Box 171, Folder 11-16)
      - Public opinion polls
        - General, 1970; 1972; undated (Box 171, Folder 17)
        - Lou Harris/Virginia Slims, 1972 (Box 172, Folder 1)
        - Polls on Vietnam war, 1970 (Box 172, Folder 2)
      - Seventeen magazine, "What's Right and Wrong with America,", 1971 (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - Women's Action Alliance
    - "The Need for a New Organization," proposal, 1971 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - Administration
      - Annual and quarterly Reports, 1978; 1983-84 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      - Board of Directors: lists, correspondence and memoranda, meeting packets (including agendas, minutes, reports), 1974-86 (Box 172, Folder 6-14)
      - Board of Directors: lists, correspondence and memoranda, meeting packets (including agendas, minutes, reports), 1974-86 (Box 173, Folder 1-12)
      - By-laws, 1979; undated (Box 173, Folder 13)
      - Clippings, 1972; 1979 (Box 173, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence of Steinem, 1970-85 (Box 173, Folder 15)
      - Executive committee: correspondence, memoranda, meeting materials, 1973-83 (Box 173, Folder 16-20)
      - Executive committee: correspondence, memoranda, meeting materials, 1973-83 (Box 174, Folder 1-24)
      - Executive Director
        - Correspondence, 1975; 1977 (Box 174, Folder 25)
        - Performance and salary review of Sylvia Kramer (Box 174, Folder 26)
        - Searches: memoranda, resumes, job description, 1973; 1979 (Box 174, Folder 27)
      - Financial statements and reports, 1972-83 (Box 175, Folder 1)
      - Ford Foundation: correspondence, 1979 (Box 175, Folder 2)
      - Fundraising: correspondence, donor lists, proposals, 1975-86 (Box 175, Folder 3-5)
      - "Hotline,", undated (Box 175, Folder 6)
      - Institutional histories (Box 175, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 175, Folder 8)
      - Organizational overview, 1975 (Box 175, Folder 9)
      - Personnel (Box 175, Folder 10)
      - Press releases and related public relations materials (Box 175, Folder 11)
      - Proposals (Box 175, Folder 12)
      - Public Education/Outreach Program: memoranda, 1979 (Box 176, Folder 1)
      - Public service announcements: memoranda and scripts (Box 176, Folder 2)
      - Questionnaires (blank), undated (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - Projects
      - Economics
        - Equal Employment Opportunities Commission, 1975 (Box 176, Folder 4)
        - Jobs for Older Women Action Project: proposal, undated (Box 176, Folder 5)
        - National Campaign against Sex Discrimination in Employment: proposal, 1975 (Box 176, Folder 6)
        - Women at Work Exposition: conference report, 1978-79 (Box 176, Folder 7)
      - Education
        - Computer Equity, 1983-85 (Box 176, Folder 8)
        - Institute in Women's History (also Women's History Week), 1979 (Box 176, Folder 9)
        - International Women's Project, 1976 (Box 176, Folder 10)
        - Non-Sexist Child Development (Box 176, Folder 11)
        - General (includes project update and program descriptions), 1973 (Box 176, Folder 12)
        - Portable Women's History Museum, undated (Box 176, Folder 13)
      - U.S. National Women's Agenda Coalition
        - Clippings, 1975 (Box 176, Folder 14)
        - Conference packet, "Beyond Suffrage", 1975 (Box 176, Folder 15)
        - Correspondence, 1976-79 (Box 176, Folder 16)
        - Minutes and memoranda, 1977-81 (Box 176, Folder 17)
        - Outreach: correspondence, 1975 (Box 176, Folder 18)
        - Press materials, undated (Box 176, Folder 19)
        - Profiles of member organizations, 1979 (Box 177, Folder 1)
        - Project update: Women's Agenda magazine, 1977-78 (Box 177, Folder 2)
        - Proposals, 1977; undated (Box 177, Folder 3)
        - Steering Committee: minutes, memoranda, updates, 1978-79 (Box 177, Folder 4-6)
        - "Task Force Plans of Action," draft, 1976 (Box 177, Folder 7-8)
        - Women's Agenda, 1978 (Box 177, Folder 9)
      - Women's Centers Project: memoranda, proposal, and directory to multi-service women's centers in New England, 1979 (Box 177, Folder 10)
      - "Report of the Women's Action Program on the Status of Women in the HEW,", undated (Box 177, Folder 11)
      - Resources: Referral and Information Services/Technical Assistance Program (TAP)
        - Proposals (Box 177, Folder 12)
        - Reading lists (Box 177, Folder 13)
        - Technical assistance
          - Activities report, 1980 (Box 177, Folder 14)
          - Bilingual Bicultural Day Care, 1971 (Box 177, Folder 15)
          - Booklets (includes "Raising Funds from Foundations"; "How to Organize a Child Care Center"; "How to Organize a Multi-Service Women's Center"; and "A Model for Non-Sexist Child Development"), undated (Box 178, Folder 1)
          - Child care: proposal and research material, 1979; undated (Box 178, Folder 2)
          - General, 1978; 1982 (Box 178, Folder 3)
          - Proposal Critique Service, 1970-80 (Box 178, Folder 4)
          - Workshops for non-profit women's organization workers, 1979-80 (Box 178, Folder 5)
        - Library: report and vertical files on women's organizations, 1971-78 (Box 178, Folder 6-11)
        - Publications: brochures, pamphlets, Equal Play, "Introduction to the Women's Movement," Women's Agenda, and "Women's Action Alliance Directory", 1973-85; undated (Box 179, Folder 1-5)
  - Women USA: articles of incorporation, clippings, correspondence, notes and memoranda, proposals, press releases, 1979-83; undated (Box 179, Folder 6-13)
  - Wonder Woman Foundation: clippings, correspondence, event programs, press materials, comic books and publications, 1973-86; undated (Box 179, Folder 14-19)
- SERIES VI. POLITICAL CAMPAIGNS, 1969-1993
  This series contains material related to electoral politics. It is divided into two subseries: Individuals and Organizations. Both record a broad range of Steinem's involvement, from a single endorsement to her active engagement in fundraising and campaigning. Four folders, arranged alphabetically, contain correspondence pertaining to candidate endorsements; an additional series of individual files contain larger amounts of correspondence and printed material pertaining to specific campaigns.
  Materials relating to political organizations in which Steinem participated or monitored include the Congressional Women's Caucus, the Women's Presidential Project, and, most notably, the Democratic National Committee. In 1969 Steinem became a member-at-large of the Democratic National Committee's Democratic Policy Council, a group of seventy-four whose responsibility it was to monitor the Nixon administration, and to create a blueprint for the next Democratic convention. There are scattered materials pertaining to both the DNC and the Policy Council, including a 1969 letter in which Steinem expresses pessimism over the Policy Council's (led by Hubert Humphrey) prospects.
  - Endorsements
    - General
      - A-D (includes Tammy Baldwin, Mel Carnahan and Rosa DeLauro) (Box 180, Folder 1)
      - E-G (Box 180, Folder 2)
      - H-M (includes Maurice Hinchey, Carol Mosely-Braun) (Box 180, Folder 3)
      - N-Z (includes Lynn Schenk, Karen Shepherd) (Box 180, Folder 4)
    - Individual files: correspondence and public relations materials
      - A-D (includes Bella Abzug, William Clinton, Ada Deer, David Dinkins, and Michael Dukakis) (Box 180, Folder 5-13)
      - A-D (includes Bella Abzug, William Clinton, Ada Deer, David Dinkins, and Michael Dukakis) (Box 181, Folder 1-5)
      - E-J (includes Ronnie Eldridge, Dianne Feinstein, Jane Harman, Gary Hart, Tom Hayden, Erma Henderson, Elizabeth Holtzman, Hubert Humphrey, and Jesse Jackson) (Box 181, Folder 6-23)
      - K-M (includes Ed Koch, George McGovern, Ruth Messinger, Barbara Mikulski, and Walter Mondale and Geraldine Ferraro) (Box 181, Folder 24-27)
      - K-M (includes Ed Koch, George McGovern, Ruth Messinger, Barbara Mikulski, and Walter Mondale and Geraldine Ferraro) (Box 182, Folder 1-4)
      - N-R (includes Bob Packwood and Ann Richards ) (Box 182, Folder 5-9)
      - S-Z (includes Pat Schroeder, Lynn Yeakel, and Andrew Young) (Box 182, Folder 10-16)
  - Organizations
    - Congressional Women's Caucus: notes, memoranda, 1993; undated (Box 182, Folder 17)
    - Democratic National Committee
      - General, 1971; undated (Box 182, Folder 18)
      - National Policy Council
        - General, 1969-72; undated (Box 182, Folder 19)
        - Resolution on Vietnam, 1970 (Box 183, Folder 1)
      - Newsletters, 1969; 1971 (Box 183, Folder 2)
      - New York City Democratic Party, 1971-72; 1979 (Box 183, Folder 3)
      - Women's Leadership Conference, 1971 (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - Women's Presidential Project, 1983 (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 183, Folder 6)
- SERIES VII. SUBJECTS, 1956-96
  This extensive series contains files, arranged alphabetically, in which Steinem kept material on subjects in which she had an interest, from Abortion to the Working Women United Institute. Also included are organizations for which Steinem served in some official capacity. Materials in this series vary widely, and include correspondence, clippings, proposals, and printed materials.
  - Abortion: clippings, congressional testimonies, correspondence (includes Daniel Patrick Moynihan), press releases, articles, organization material, poll data, and printed material (a number of subfiles include material collected on the 1972-73 Michigan referendum) (Box 183, Folder 7-18)
  - Abortion: clippings, congressional testimonies, correspondence (includes Daniel Patrick Moynihan), press releases, articles, organization material, poll data, and printed material (a number of subfiles include material collected on the 1972-73 Michigan referendum) (Box 184, Folder 1-15)
  - Abou-Saif, Laila: correspondence, writings by and about Abou-Saif, 1978-84 (Box 184, Folder 16)
  - Abzug, Bella 1970-84 (includes material re: "Friday night massacre," Feb 1979), 1970-84 (Box 185, Folder 1)
    [see also Evans and Novack]
  - Agricultural Workers Freedom to Work Association: correspondence, 1969 (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - AIDS Commission: correspondence, 1988 (Box 185, Folder 3)
  - "Alaska Women Speak," newsletters, 1993-94 (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Alda, Alan: article 1981, and remarks at Kenyon College, 1982 (Box 185, Folder 5)
  - Alice Paul Foundation: correspondence, brochures, and clippings, 1986-89 (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - All Craft Center: correspondence, proposals, printed material, 1979-95 (Box 185, Folder 7)
  - Alliance for the Rights of Children: correspondence, clippings, press statements, 1993 (Box 185, Folder 8)
  - "All that Glitters"/Ann Marcus: correspondence and scripts, 1977 (Box 185, Folder 9)
  - Alpert, Jane (includes manuscript, "Letter from the Underground"), undated (Box 185, Folder 10)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: correspondence and memoranda, 1972-73 (Box 185, Folder 11)
  - American Psychiatric Association: materials pertaining to support of ERA, 1979-80 (Box 185, Folder 12)
  - American Society of Magazine Editors: minutes, memoranda, and printed material, 1978-86 (includes summary of Steinem's remarks at members' luncheon, 29 January 1980 (Box 185, Folder 13)
  - American Writers Congress: proposal, 1981 (Box 185, Folder 14)
  - Angela Davis Emergency Committee: correspondence, clippings, financial data, 1971 (Box 185, Folder 15)
  - Anguiano, Lupe: memoranda, 1983 (Box 185, Folder 16)
  - Anthony, Susan B.: article from TABS: Aids for Ending Sexism in School, 1978 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - Anti-nuclear movement: clippings, 1979 (Box 186, Folder 2)
  - Asian and Pacific Center for Women and Development: correspondence and reports, 1979 (Box 186, Folder 3)
  - Baby M: clippings, correspondence, legal documents, including amicus brief filed by Jeremy Rifkin, 1987 (Box 186, Folder 4)
  - Baird, Zoe: draft of statement, undated (Box 186, Folder 5)
  - Battered women: correspondence, 1977; 1980 (Box 186, Folder 6)
  - Bibliographies and citations, 1972-78 (Box 186, Folder 7)
  - Black feminism: clippings and press materials, 1973; undated (Box 186, Folder 8)
  - Black South African writers (training for): correspondence, 1978-79 (Box 186, Folder 9)
  - Blakely, Mary Kay: writings and correspondence, 1980-81; 1989; undated (Box 186, Folder 10)
  - Bolen, Jean Shinoda: correspondence and clippings, 1978-84 (Box 186, Folder 11)
  - Bosnia: clippings and correspondence, 1992-94 (Box 186, Folder 12)
  - Boston University Local District 65, UAW: correspondence, notes, printed material, 1983 (Box 186, Folder 13)
  - Boston Women's Fund: correspondence, 1988 (Box 186, Folder 14)
  - Bower, Ruth: correspondence, 1990; 1993 (Box 186, Folder 15)
  - Bread and Roses: press kit, 1978 (Box 186, Folder 16)
  - Breast implants: clippings and correspondence, 1991-92 (Box 186, Folder 17)
  - Brimmer, Brenda: correspondence, 1978-79 (Box 186, Folder 18)
  - Bunting, Mary I: article, 1961 (Box 187, Folder 1)
  - Caine, Michael: correspondence and clippings 1992-93 (includes letter from Steinem to Caine) (Box 187, Folder 2)
  - Cambodian Crisis Committee: mailgrams, 1980 (Box 187, Folder 3)
  - Campaign for Economic Democracy (Tom Hayden): clippings and correspondence, 1979 (Box 187, Folder 4)
  - Carpenter, Liz: transcript of interview for Evaluation magazine, n.d. Chavez, Cesar: mailing lists, notes, United Farm Workers press materials circa 1972-1979 (includes letter from Margaret Sloan) (Box 187, Folder 5)
  - Carpenter, Liz: transcript of interview for Evaluation magazine, n.d. Chavez, Cesar: mailing lists, notes, United Farm Workers press materials circa 1972-1979 (includes letter from Margaret Sloan) (Box 187, Folder 6)
  - Child care: syllabus and miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 187, Folder 7)
  - Chiswick Family Center: correspondence and clippings, 1989-93 (Box 187, Folder 8)
  - Chrysalis: correspondence, 1977 (Box 187, Folder 9)
  - Chwatsky, Anne: correspondence and clippings 1979 (includes letter from Erica Jong) (Box 187, Folder 10)
  - Citizens for Gay Rights Legislation: statement of support, undated (Box 187, Folder 11)
  - Coalition Against Censorship: correspondence, newsletter, and conference proceedings, 1975-77 (Box 187, Folder 12)
  - Coalition Against Domestic Violence, Inc.: symposium packet, 1990 (Box 187, Folder 13)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women: correspondence and memoranda, 1974 (Box 187, Folder 14)
  - Corea, Gena: papers on Depo Provera, 1979 (Box 187, Folder 15)
  - Committee of 200: guest list and correspondence, 1984; 1986 (Box 187, Folder 16)
  - Comparable worth: correspondence and research reports, 1983-85 (Box 187, Folder 17)
  - Congressional Union: correspondence and press materials, 1981 (Box 187, Folder 18)
  - Consumer Action Now: correspondence, press releases, annual report, 1983-84 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Cosmopolitan: 1980 survey results on sexual behavior and correspondence, 1978 (includes Helen Gurley Brown) (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Costanza, Margaret ("Midge"): correspondence and clippings, 1978; 1980 (Box 188, Folder 3)
    [see also Feminist Art Institute]
  - Council on Economic Priorities: correspondence, 1988-89 (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Council on Environmental Alternatives: information kits circa 1980 Davis, Angela [see Angela Davis Emergency Committee] (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Democracy '76: correspondence and printed materials 1976 (includes Andrea Dworkin) (Box 188, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Agenda: correspondence and printed materials 1977 (includes Michael Harrington) (Box 188, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee: miscellaneous 1977-78 (includes Michael Harrington) (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Dinnerstein, Dorothy: correspondence and recommendation re: Rockefeller Foundation fellowship, 1978 (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Donahue, Phil: correspondence, clippings, transcript of interview by Steinem, 1977-78; undated (Box 188, Folder 10)
  - Doubleday, Nelson: clippings, 1983-86 (Box 188, Folder 11)
  - "Destined to Live: 100 Roads to Recovery": correspondence and printed material, 1988 (Box 188, Folder 12)
  - Dimock Community Health Center: correspondence, clippings, printed material, 1988 (Box 188, Folder 13)
  - Drukulic, Slairnka (Yugoslavian feminist): list of addresses for her mailing, undated (Box 188, Folder 14)
  - Dry Dock Savings Bank: Certificate of Incorporation, Citizens Crime Commission of New York City, 1978 (Box 188, Folder 15)
  - Dworkin, Andrea (includes book manuscript, Chains of Iron, Chains of Grief), 1978-81; undated (Box 188, Folder 16-18)
  - "Eating Raoul": Limited Partnership Agreement, 1992 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Egan, Harry: newsletter, 1979 (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Eikenberry, Jill: research materials, 1988 (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - The Emancipation of Man: address by Olaf Palme before Women's National Democratic Club, 1970 (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Egypt: correspondence, notes, clippings, 1980 (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Entertainment Tonight: correspondence, 1985-86 (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Equal Rights Amendment: articles, clippings, miscellany, 1975-81 (Box 189, Folder 7-10)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society: correspondence and reports 1976-78 (on equal employment) (Box 189, Folder 11)
  - Esterhas, Joseph (Box 189, Folder 12)
  - Ethnic groups (Box 189, Folder 13)
  - Evans & Novak: correspondence and clippings, 1978 (Box 189, Folder 14)
  - "Family Ties": correspondence, 1987 (Box 189, Folder 15)
  - Farrow, Mia: clippings and correspondence, 1993 (Box 189, Folder 16)
  - Fasteau, Brenda Feigen: correspondence, proposals, and recommendations, 1976-77 (Box 189, Folder 17)
  - Feminist Art Institute: correspondence and press release, 1977; 1981 (Box 189, Folder 18)
    [see also Costanza, Margaret]
  - Feminist Bulletin: issues and press releases, 1972-77 (Box 189, Folder 19)
  - Feminist films: note, undated (Box 189, Folder 20)
  - Feminist publications (Box 189, Folder 21)
  - Feminist science fiction: bibliographies and miscellany, 1976-80 (Box 189, Folder 22)
  - The Feminist Center for Human Growth and Development, Inc.: overview, 1980 (Box 189, Folder 23)
  - "The Feminists: A Political Organization to Annihilate Sex Roles": promotional materials 1969 Film news releases, circa 1982 (Box 189, Folder 24)
  - "The Feminists: A Political Organization to Annihilate Sex Roles": promotional materials 1969 Film news releases, circa 1982 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Firestone, Shulamith: "Declaration of Revolutionary Aesthetics,", undated (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Foat, Ginny: correspondence and clippings, 1983 (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Fonda, Jane: correspondence, writings, and clippings, 1979; undated (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation writing awards: proposal list, press releases, clippings, and memoranda, 1979-81 (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Foreign feminists: correspondence and printed material 1973-77 (includes typescript "Women in the Factory," on women in Denmark, 1973) (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Foreign feminist publications: correspondence and publications, 1973-77 (Box 190, Folder 7)
  - Freedom Socialist Party: correspondence and printed material, 1986 (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Freeman, Jo: correspondence and article, 1993; undated (Box 190, Folder 9)
  - Friedan, Betty: correspondence, clippings, and notes circa 1973-81 (includes responses to allegations made during Friedan's Donahue appearance) (Box 190, Folder 10)
  - Full employment (includes correspondence from Coretta Scott King throughout)
    - Conference on Full Employment, 1974 (Box 190, Folder 11)
    - Papers (Box 190, Folder 12)
    - Full Employment Action Council: correspondence, agendas, memoranda, 1974-77 (Box 190, Folder 13)
    - National Committee for Full Employment: correspondence, agendas, memoranda, 1974-76 (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - Hawkins Bill ("Equal Opportunity and Full Employment Act of 1976"): memoranda, press materials, bill, 1974-76 (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Printed materials, 1972-76 (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Fundamentalists Anonymous: newsletter, correspondence, and benefit program, 1988; 1991 (Box 191, Folder 4)
  - Gallagher Report: newsletters, 1978 (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth: article, addresses, and testimony, 1966-67; 1977 (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - Galluadet College labor organizing: correspondence, pro- and anti-union literature 1984 (includes press statement by Steinem) (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - Gays in the military: article, 1993 (Box 191, Folder 8)
  - General: includes labor, miscellaneous, politics, and press clippings, 1967-84 (Box 191, Folder 9-12)
  - Genital mutilation: includes correspondence, typescripts, newsletters, and miscellany, 1977-79; undated (Box 192, Folder 1-4)
  - The Getting Gazette: newsletters, 1993; 1996 (Box 192, Folder 5)
  - "Getting Out"/Project Green Hope: correspondence and printed material, 1979 (Box 192, Folder 6)
  - Gillooley, Jane: memoranda and clippings, 1994-95 (Box 192, Folder 7)
  - Girls' clubs: memoranda, correspondence, and printed material, 1977-81 (Box 192, Folder 8)
  - Glen Ridge (NJ) rape case: correspondence, 1993 (Box 192, Folder 9)
  - Global Fund for Women: correspondence and promotional material, 1987-88 (Box 192, Folder 10)
  - GRANTA: correspondence, 1984 (Box 192, Folder 11)
  - Gregory-Lewis, Sasha: correspondence and manuscript, "Right Wing Links to Stop-ERA Documented,", 1977 (Box 192, Folder 12)